I've been playing with mCP integration
into AI coding IDE for the past few days
it has totally changed my workflow and
boost my productivity so my cursor not
only generate codes but also calling
text to image model to generate all the
gaming assets that is needed for
developing the game that you're seeing
here and not only that when there bugs
my cursor also looking to console log
and network request to debug Arrow it
can even read my superbase database
directly and doing internet search
looking to my figma file all those
thanks to the mCP server function so
today I will take you through what is
mCP how can you integrate existing mcps
that other people already created as
well as the easiest way to set up your
own mCP server in just few minutes for
people who are watching this video you
probably more or less heard about mCP
which is a modo context protocol
introduced by entropic last year it
basically provide a universal interface
for people to connect their agent to
allour different data source and
external systems you can think of mCP
like a USBC port for all sorts of
different air applications just like
USBC provides standardized way to
connect your device to also different
accessories mCP provides standardized
ways to connect AI model to different
data source and external system what's
really interesting is AI coding has
evolved a lot for the past few months
from initially just a chat co-pilot to
composer that can create a fil to
nowadays all the modern a ID like cursor
and window server or build powerful
agents that can do some plannings and
take a lot of different type of actions
at default cursor coding agents we have
a list of actions that can take but what
if you wanted to do more that's where
the mCP comes in you can build all sorts
of different COs in inations so that
cursor can access almost whatever you
want they really change the game for AI
codings mCP can be used for many
different scenarios for example some of
mCP server might be just prompts where
the agent can just call certain mCP like
analyze code and it will return a proper
user message with specific prompt that
can guide the agent behavior for next
actions but on the outs side mCP can
also be used to connect to different
external Resource as well as assistance
to calling different API and point when
you look at entropic mCP doc it is
fairly complicated and not exactly clear
how can you install and create your own
mCP very easily that's why today I want
to take you through some of my favorite
mCP as well as the easiest way to build
your own mCP that can connect your
cursor into any source of system you
want so without further Ado let's get it
there are a few Marketplace already
existed they show you a list of mCP that
other people have created that you can
use from gl. a SMI cursor. directory as
well ASM systems where they have hosted
mCP server that you can use and the way
you can use those platform is that you
can search for the mcpu that you want to
use for example if I I want to add a
sequential thinking mCP which is type of
mCP that will force agent to think
through a few different steps and do
some plannings I can choose a ID that
I'm using in this case a recursor and I
can just copy this command line over go
to my cursor select feature and in the
mCP server I can click on ADD mCP I can
give a name and the name here didn't
really matter I can just call it
sequential thinking and there are two
different types you can choose in most
cases for now you'll probably choose
command which means it will run a local
command to call the server but if you're
using some host mCP server then you can
choose SS but most of the time it is
almost always command so we can add this
and click add the botton you will see
that this is a new mCP server added
called sequential syncing and this is
one two called sequential sying so what
I can do is that we can start a new chat
with agent and just give a prompt I want
to build a game now let's plan it using
sequential syncing don't generate any
code yet and then you will be prompt to
call this mCP server and for this
specific tool if you open it you can see
that it is basically trying to use
function call to force agent generate
multiple different sorts it is counting
how many sorts that you need to do in
total and the next s needed will be true
which means if I finish this it will try
to continue doing another s repeat this
process for probably eight times if you
want you can also turn on this YOLO mode
which means you don't need to approve
every single time but I would suggest
you to do the manual one first but to
make something more interesting you can
also search for a r mCP and one thing to
not is that currently there's no
standardized way to install or set up
mcps each mCP is kind of set up
differently and the quality of mcps on
those websites are also quite unstable
many of them didn't really work at all
and this makes adoption a lot harder but
I will show you a few example of common
ways to install those mcps basic I want
to find command line to use sometimes
they will provide MPX package D which
you can copy and start using but quite
often you will have problem that it
didn't really work for example if I copy
this one and add a mCP server Reddit MC
you might see that this mCP has no tool
available which means you can't do
anything with it but you might also say
Json like this and for this one you
basically need to convert them into a
single line command which in this case
will be the uvx from git link here mCP
Reddit and you can of separate them out
with space so I can copy this and add a
new server called it redit command and
paste in you can see that this has been
added with two tools fetch Reddit hot
strats and fetch Reddit post content and
we can give a try what are some latest
hot content on Reddit it will try to
call this mcp2 F Reddit hot Strat and if
I click accept you can see it return
some of the content from reddits so this
is basically how you can use those
existing platform to find mCP that you
might be able to use but one really
annoying thing of using other people's
mCP at the moment is that even though
there are mCP directories many of those
mcps didn't actually work or it is very
complicated to set up with incomplete
documents I spent quite a lot of time
testing different mcps and future down
list of mcps that's both useful and
useable I'll share this list in the AI
Builder Club Community and building and
I'll continue sharing new interesting
mCP I found so if you're interested you
can click on the link below to join my
community but what I want to show you is
a few MC that I personally use a lot
that really boost my productivity and
the first mCP I want to introduce is
browser tools this mCP that give your
cursor access to your browser console
log and network tabs directly so that
they can run your app debugging much
easier and also allow you to communicate
with cursor about specific element that
you want to change on the you firstly
you will need to clone their Chrome
plugin so you can either run the command
line get clone or you can use GitHub
desktop app and clone this specific
Ripple and once it's done you can click
on the settings in your Chrome extension
and click on load on compact then choose
Chrome extension folder from the browser
2 mCP folder as you see the browser 2
mCP show up here and next we want to add
mCP server to cursor you click on
settings feature mCP server and just
give a name browser tools and the type
we choose command here we're need to
copy this and paste in you can see it
has list of tools from get console logs
console Arrow Network Arrow screenshots
as well as select element and the last
step is that we want to run the browser
to mCP server so you can just open
Terminal in any directory to MP X at
agentes browser to server and then this
server is running now if you go to any
web page and open inspector you can see
at top there have bar called browser 2
mCP is debugging the browser which means
you can actually go to cursor in agent
mode just ask what's in my console lck
and it will run this get console log to
it'll be able to see all the console
logs you have and also check if there's
any arrow in console L apart from
reading the console and network logs it
also has cool features like guest L
Elements which means you can go to your
web browser right click in back so in
here we select this specific element and
then I can give prompt update only the
style of element I choose in the browser
right now to something fancier that
looks like a real poket car then it will
run this function called guest L element
and return a specific diff and from
there it identify it is car component
and update that specific component and
this is kind of fairly simple example
but you can imagine for more complex
applications this will allow you to
communicate with cursor much easier and
one of the coolest thing that mCP allow
you to do is connect to any other
service to enhance your cursor workflow
for example what if cursor can call text
to image model to generate all sorts of
gaming assets like the background image
and this is where you can create custom
mCP server to connect any sort of
service and here you can see I actually
create my own mCP server with one of
function called generate image so what I
would do is I take a screenshot of how
the game looks like right now help me
generate different images of dogs for
cards instead of emoji and click submit
and then it will call this function to
generate a image and it will return one
and it will try to generate a few
more all right so it generate a few
different image so we have this new game
called poy memory game and if you click
on each one of them you can see that
they are unique image that generated by
the AI model and all those image are
actually coordinated by cursor itself
which is absolutely amazing and even
though setting up mCP server does sounds
like a lot of work when you look at mCP
doc but it's actually not that
complicated and you can use cloud flat
where they provide a worker and mCP that
basically give you the boy play of the
mCP server you just need to build
function yourself and I'm going to
quickly show you how you can do that so
I'm going to create a new folder with
command line mpm create Cloud flare at
latest so this one we set up a cloud
flare project I will just name it my mCP
and the example I will choose hell word
and Hell World worker and language I
will choose typescript and do we want to
use git for the version of course we
want and do we want to deploy for this
one I'm going to choose use no but if
you want you can also deploy it to use
on other server or even share with
others later cool the next step is our
CD my mCP which is folder name and then
do mpm so you can just paste this in if
you restart Cloud you should be able to
see a little toy icon show up here where
it include all the functions that we
have defined in those example file but
if you want to activate this mCP for
cursor what you will do is that you will
put the command of this one space this
one and this one and putting that
together for my specific examp example I
would just put this command line into
cursor's mCP so I can add a new mCP and
my mCP type will be command and paste
that in and add you can see this tool
has been added successfully and here is
one tool called say hello if you open
your mCP folder and select indexs this
as we mentioned before is where you're
going to store all the functions so here
you can see this one function called say
hello so the thing above is how we
communicate when to use this tool the
inputs and expand output format and here
we have one function of say hello so
what we can do is that we can open
cursor or just say say hello for workers
mCP server for me and now you can see it
tried to call this tool called say hello
and it return this result which is what
you define here this is a very basic mCP
function but you can imagine now you can
write whatever function you want conect
to external API service or even run
local models directly and this is
exactly how I write mCP to call image
generation model post down replicate I
can just choose the API service I can
just copy the code example open cursor
paste in and give prom help me write a
new function that will generate image
using a model host down replicate don't
use any environment variable just put
variable inside index.ts directly uh so
this is not best practice but because
cursor mCP unfortunately didn't allow
you to set up environment variable very
easily so we have to set the environment
variable inside the file direct lay and
I will also give some additional prompt
the replicate API return a prediction
object that needs to be pulled for
completion not an immediate result and
making sure pass result poply so this
just some a common mistake I saw L model
often make with replicate API aut box
okay I'll click accept and at top we
need to put the API key here and here
you can see that it generate new
function with description generate image
using recraft V3 model and with two
input param prompt and size and return
the URL of gener image once it's
finished I do PM round deploy this word
deploys again and just for testing
purpose I will use cloud to just quickly
test it so I will close cloud and open
Cloud again just quickly check the
generate image is here so I say help me
generate an image of Doc Val
AI allow for this chat and I got an
arrow saying fail to start image
generation the specific version didn't
exist I think it is using the wrong URL
for some reason so I'm just going to
copy this in again make sure you use the
right URL and write inputs just like
above code example okay once it's
finished we can do npm R deploy to
deploy the latest version and I'm going
to restart Cloud to say help me generate
a dog image well the reason I use cloud
is because I don't want to keep restart
my cursor it's just a bit easier but you
don't have to you can also just testing
cursor directly okay so you can see that
it return this message of the image URL
generated if I open that link it will
show me this image generation so this
how you can connect any sorts of
functionalities and external assistant
to your cursor I'm really excited to see
what kind of things you're going to come
up with and most annoying thing about
mCP now is that many of them just kind
of don't work out of box it's almost
easier to build your own so I spent
quite a few time to like test different
mCP server choose the ones that I use a
lot and I'm putting the AI build club
and building so if you're interested you
can click on the link below to join the
community where I will be maintaining a
list of high quality mCP that I found is
extremely useful for AI coding as well
as some custom ones that I develop
myself you can click the link in the
description below to join my community I
hope you enjoy this content if you enjoy
please comment below I'll post more in
depth tutorial about mcps in AI coding
thank you and I see you next time